when I was at the CIA we had an ongoing
joke during the uh the George W Bush
Administration that none of us had ever
seen an Administration that worked so
hard to not talk to our enemies we had a
state department with thousands and
thousands of employees who just sat
there twiddling their thumbs and doing
nothing because we don't talk to the
Cubans or the Iranians or the Chinese or
the Venezuelans or the Russians or the
libyans or a dozen other countries we
don't talk to them I went on an overseas
trip when I was working on the Senate
Foreign Relations Committee I went to
jibuti Somalia Ethiopia and I was
forbidden from going to Atria not by the
Eritrean government but by the state
department and the only reason they gave
me is oh you don't want to go to erria
that's the North Korea of Africa that's
what I was told
I was recently invited to dinner at
their at the arrian ambassador's
residence here in Washington I can go do
that but I can't go to Atria because we
don't like
them as I said I hope that this begins
to change under Donald Trump I'm not
sure that it will change markedly and
even if it does change I'm just not of
the belief that those changes are going
to be necessarily longstanding
and that's why it's up to us to keep
riding our elected officials to keep
writing and speaking and marching and
making sure that our elected officials
know what we want in a government
foreign policy and in a government
intelligence policy we should be at
these at these hearings we should be
taking notes and writing op ads and
speaking to friends and doing podcasts
and making sure that our voices are
heard